Political Research Associates Records MS014
Tufts Archival Research Center
- Subject files, 1949 -- 2010; MS014.003; 78.0 Cubic Feet
  - WIN PAC, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003896; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - Winds of Fire catalogue, circa 1997 -- 1999; MS014.003897; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Wings of Hope, circa 1986 -- 1989; MS014.003898; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Winpisinger, circa 1987; MS014.003899; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 19)
  - Winsor, Curtin, Jr., circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003900; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 20)
  - Wisconsin Policy Research Institute, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003901; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 21)
  - Wise Use, circa 1992 -- 1996; MS014.003902; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 22)
  - Wise Use Conference No. 1, circa 1994; MS014.003903; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 23)
  - Wise Use Conference Np. 2, circa 1994; MS014.003904; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - Wiswell Ruffin House, circa 1986; MS014.003905; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 25)
  - Witness for Peace, 1990; MS014.003906; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 26)
  - Witch Hunt Watch, 1983; MS014.003907; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 27)
  - Woellner, David, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003908; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 28)
  - Wolfowitz. Paul, 2001; MS014.003909; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Women Exploited By Abortion, circa 1992 -- 1993; MS014.003910; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 30)
  - Women for Christ, 1984; MS014.003911; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 31)
  - Women of Faith, 1997; MS014.003912; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 32)
  - Women of the Harvest, 1999; MS014.003913; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 33)
  - Women Investors Research Institute, circa 1974; MS014.003914; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 34)
  - Women's Freedom Network, circa 1995 -- 2000; MS014.003915; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 35)
  - The Women's Quarterly, circa 1999; MS014.003916; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 36)
  - Word of God/Sword of the Spirit, circa 1988 -- 1990; MS014.003917; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 37)
  - Wood, Mary McHale, circa 1982; MS014.003918; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 38)
  - Woodson, Robert, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003919; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 39)
  - Word of Christ Mission, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003920; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 40)
  - World, circa 1999 -- 2009; MS014.003921; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 41)
  - World Affairs, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003922; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 42)
  - World Concern, circa 1981 -- 1982; MS014.003923; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 43)
  - PRI Electoral Reforms, 1994; MS014.003924; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 44)
  - World Church of the Creator, circa 1999 -- 2003; MS014.003925; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 45)
  - World Freedom Foundation, circa 1986 -- 1990; MS014.003926; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 46)
  - World Gospel Mission, circa 1987 -- 1993; MS014.003927; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 47)
  - World Impact, Inc., circa 1988; MS014.003928; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 48)
  - World Leadership Council, circa 1984 -- 1989; MS014.003929; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 49)
  - World Medical Health Foundation, circa 1986 -- 1989; MS014.003930; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 50)
  - World Magazine, 2002; MS014.003931; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 51)
  - World Medical Relief, circa 1982 -- 1991; MS014.003932; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 52)
  - World Muslim Congress, 1982; MS014.003933; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 53)
  - World Neighors, circa 1982 -- 1994; MS014.003934; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 54)
  - World Pac, 1982; MS014.003935; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 55)
  - World Press Freedom Committee, circa 1990; MS014.003936; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 56)
  - World Rehabilitation Fund, circa 1987 -- 1989; MS014.003937; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 57)
  - World Relief, circa 1987 -- 1989; MS014.003938; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 58)
  - World Relief, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003939; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 59)
  - World Service, circa 1980; MS014.003940; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 60)
  - World Share, circa 1990 -- 1991; MS014.003941; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 61)
  - World Vision, circa 2000 -- 2001; MS014.003942; 1 Folder(s) (Box 73, Folder 62)
  - World Vision '98, circa 1998; MS014.003972; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - World Vision -- General, circa 1979 -- 1984; MS014.003973; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - World Vision International El Salvador/Guatemala/Honduras, circa 1986 -- 1988; MS014.003974; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - World Vision International, circa 1986 -- 1994; MS014.003975; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - World Vision, circa 1981 -- 1994; MS014.003976; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - World Vision, circa 1985 -- 1990; MS014.003977; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - World Vision -- Finance, circa 1978 -- 1989; MS014.003978; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - World Wildlife Fund, circa 1987 -- 1990; MS014.003979; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - World Without War Council, circa 1987 -- 1990; MS014.003980; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Wrenn, Carter, 1984; MS014.003981; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Wright, Clymer L., 1982; MS014.003982; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Wycliffe Bible Translators, circa 1981 -- 2007; MS014.003983; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Wycliffe Bible Translators, circa 1987 -- 2006; MS014.003984; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Xenophobia, 1993; MS014.003985; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - Y2K, circa 1999; MS014.003986; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - YAHSHUA, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003987; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Yahohushua, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003988; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Yockey, Francis Parker, circa 1981; MS014.003989; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - Young America's Foundation, circa 1993 -- 2009; MS014.003990; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - Young American's Foundation Conference July 93, circa 1993 -- 2009; MS014.003991; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 20)
  - Young Americans for Freedom, circa 1979 -- 1990; MS014.003992; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 21)
  - Young Conservative Alliance, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003993; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 22)
  - Young President's Organization, circa 1991; MS014.003994; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 23)
  - Young Republicans, circa 1970 --1990; MS014.003995; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 24)
  - Your Heritage, 1991; MS014.003996; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 25)
  - Youth for Understanding, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.003997; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 26)
  - Youth with a Mission, circa 1983 -- 1999; MS014.003998; 1 Folder(s) (Box 74, Folder 27)
  - Militia research, circa 1993 -- 1995; MS014.004629; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Soldier of Fortune magazine, circa 1995; MS014.004630; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Front Lines research, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004631; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Toward Tradition - Toward a new Alliance conference materials, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004632; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Release - Planned Parenthood visual work release, circa 1995; MS014.004633; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Connections conference, circa 1988 -- 1995; MS014.004634; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Video news release model, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.004635; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Visuals only anti-abortion handouts, circa 1989 -- 1995; MS014.004636; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Library notes research, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.004637; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - FEC (federal election commission) notes, circa 1993 --1994; MS014.004638; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Return records visuals, circa 1993 -- 1994; MS014.004639; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 11)
    This folder contains direct mail, communications, and fliers from anti-abortion groups across the United States. Materials includes images and rhetoric that is sexist, threatening, and graphic in nature, depicting images of fetal remains and mutilated dolls. For more information on DCA's content warning policy please visit our website.
  - Key articles - Anti-abortion conspiracy, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004640; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - U.S. military links communications and notes, circa 1995; MS014.004641; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 13)
  - Research notes and militia articles, circa 1995; MS014.004642; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - Anti-abortion articles, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004643; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - Charter reconstructionism articles, circa 1994; MS014.004644; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 16)
  - American Foundation for Resistance International, circa 1989; MS014.004645; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 17)
  - Militias - Michigan articles, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004646; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 18)
  - Montana Human Rights Network reports and newsletters, circa 1991 -- 1995; MS014.004647; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 19)
  - USTP (U.S. Taxpayer Party) - The Sling newsletters, circa 1993 -- 1994; MS014.004648; 1 Folder(s) (Box 75, Folder 20)
  - Soldier of Fortune magazine, circa 1989 -- 1995; MS014.004649; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Aid and Abet police newsletter, circa 1994; MS014.004650; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Jack McLamb report, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004651; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Thompson, Linda notes and reports, circa 1994; MS014.004652; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Chenoweth, Helen communications, circa 1995; MS014.004653; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Gritz, Bo notes and articles, circa 1994; MS014.004654; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Duke, David notes and reports, circa 1987 -- 1994; MS014.004655; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Gritz, Bo articles, circa 1992; MS014.004656; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - The Populist Party articles and reports, circa 1984 -- 1986; MS014.004657; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Militias - Alphabetical states communications and notes, circa 1995; MS014.004658; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Militias - Arizona articles and reports, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004659; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Militias - California notes, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.004660; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Militias - Colorado articles and notes, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004661; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Militias - Indiana articles and notes, circa 1977 -- 1995; MS014.004662; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - Militias - Kansas articles, circa 1995; MS014.004663; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - Militias - New Hampshire articles, 1995; MS014.004664; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Militias - North Carolina articles, circa 1995; MS014.004665; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Militias - Oregon communications, circa 1995; MS014.004666; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - Militias - Pennsylvania articles, circa 1995; MS014.004667; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 19)
  - Militias - Tennessee articles, circa 1991 -- 1995; MS014.004668; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 20)
  - Militias - Virginia articles, circa 1995; MS014.004669; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 21)
  - Militias - Washington communications, 1995; MS014.004670; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 22)
  - Couture, John articles and notes, circa 1981 -- 1994; MS014.004671; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 23)
  - Wisconsin posse articles, circa 1980 -- 1995; MS014.004672; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 24)
  - Posse Comitatus articles, circa 1981 -- 1984; MS014.004673; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 25)
  - Posse noose report newsletters, circa 1981 -- 1983; MS014.004674; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 26)
  - Illegal tax protest movement, circa 1985; MS014.004675; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 27)
  - ADL (Anti-Defamation League) report, 1994; MS014.004676; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 28)
  - BAACOR communications, 1994; MS014.004677; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 29)
  - Coalition for Human Dignity newsletters, 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004678; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 30)
  - John Goetz communications and notes, 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004679; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 31)
  - Klanwatch newsletters, 1989 -- 1994; MS014.004680; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 32)
  - NWCAMH (Northwest Coalition Against Malicious Harassment) notes and materials, circa 1995; MS014.004681; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 33)
  - PART (People Against Racist Terror) communications, circa 1995; MS014.004682; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 34)
  - Paul De Armond draft report, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004683; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 35)
  - Schumer press conference notes and communication, circa 1995; MS014.004684; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 36)
  - WACO Waco, TX communications, circa 1995; MS014.004685; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 37)
  - Schumer hearing testimony, circa 1995; MS014.004686; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 38)
  - Robert W. Spear materials, circa 1993; MS014.004687; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 39)
  - Good ole boys / ATF / Gadsen communications, circa 1995; MS014.004688; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 40)
  - Oregon / Washington Prep articles, circa 1994; MS014.004689; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 41)
  - Peter Peters articles, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.004690; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 42)
  - Kirk Lyon S. Cause communications, circa 1995; MS014.004691; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 43)
  - National Alliance communications, circa 1995; MS014.004692; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 44)
  - "FIJA" Jury power articles, circa 1970 -- 1990; MS014.004693; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 45)
  - CNC (Constitutionists Networking Center) communications, circa 1994; MS014.004694; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 46)
  - Theology Christian Century article, circa 1995; MS014.004695; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 47)
  - Neo-nazis articles, circa 1990; MS014.004696; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 48)
  - Anti-abortion / white supremacy communications, circa 1994; MS014.004697; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 49)
  - General miscellaneous articles, circa 1995; MS014.004698; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 50)
  - Road to Victory materials and reports, circa 1994 -- 1995; MS014.004699; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 51)
  - Militias - reports and articles, circa 1983 -- 1996; MS014.004700; 1 Folder(s) (Box 76, Folder 52)
- Videos, 2005 -- 2006; MS014.002525; 3 Digital Object(s); 1.41 Gigabytes
  This series is open for research.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series contains an infomercial and videos of events related to conservative Christian groups.
  - Sound the Alarm: A Call to Intercession, Spokane Rally, 2005; MS014.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 177.39 Megabytes; 21.5 Minutes
    This video contains a speech given by a pastor of Westgate Chapel in Washington at a church service calling on other pastors in the state to intercede on behalf of the state and the nation.
    This video is of a speech reflecting conservative Christian values and may touch on topics of sexism, homophobia, and racism.
  - Justice Sunday III, 2006-01-08; MS014.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.13 Gigabytes; 88 Minutes
    This video is of a church service reflecting conservative Christian values and contains homophobic and pro-life rhetoric. For more information on DCA's content warning policy please visit our website.
    The Justice Sunday III service was sponsored by the Family Research Council and Focus on the Family Action, and hosted at Greater Exodus Baptist Church in Philadelphia, PA. The service was hosted by the Family Research Council President, Tony Perkins and the Senior Pastor of Greater Exodus Baptist Church, Herbert Lusk. It also features many guest speakers who are politicians and religious leaders.
  - The Watchmen Project: A Ministry of the Family Research Council, 2006; MS014.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 102.77 Megabytes; 11.5 Minutes
    This video reflects conservative Christian values and may touch on topics of sexism, homophobia, racism, and pro-life rhetoric.
    This video presented by the Family Research Council and hosted by its president, Tony Perkins, is an infomercial directed at pastors.
- Website, 2013 -- 2019; MS014.003943; 1 Web sites
  Website crawled by DCA to document the presence of Political Research Associates on the web. The website in this series is crawled on an annual basis.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Archived websites can be viewed online using the Internet Archive's Wayback Machine.
  - Political Research Associates | Challenging the Right, Advancing Social Justice, 2013-06-04 -- 2019-09-18; MS014.003944; 1 Web sites